hey guys Bret contz here uh today's
video is on the goblet squat this is a
awesome exercise that everyone should do
um either as part of their warm-up or as
part of a strengthening routine and it
was popularized by Dan John he's a
legend in the strength and conditioning
industry and uh basically it goes like
this so uh you can use a kle Bell or a
dumbbell but uh since more more people
have access to dumbbells I what I'm
going to show you how to do it with the
dumbbell just going to turn the uh the
dumbbell uh upside down like this hold
on to the top of the plate now I'm going
to pinch my elbows together so they're
not out wide because my elbows are going
to track inside of my
legs so get a comfortable squat stance
you don't want it too wide CU you're
going deep uh but you want it wide
enough to where you know you can sink
down in between your hips you can keep
the feet anywhere from straight to
around a 30° angle uh just get what's
comfortable for
you again hold the dumbbell up at your
chest you don't hold it away from you
keep it at your chest tuck your elbows
in keep the chest up now I'm going to
sink as low as I can while forcing the
knees out one of the reasons why this
exercise is so good is because um I have
to get the knees out if I don't get the
knees out and I keep them in my elbows
are going to hit so it's a great uh
teaching exercise for good squat form
because I have to sink my elbows in
between my knees now don't cave down
here keep the up the upper chest keep it
keep it tall and this way you're going
to keep a strong Arch drive through the
heels come back up so again I'm going to
do three reps from straight on sink down
come up S down come
up
and now I'm going to turn to the side
okay again this is the goblet squat it's
an excellent exercise beginners should
do it as a strengthening exercise more
advanced people should do it as part of
their Dynamic War up